verbalplanet.com 2016-11-18

# Verbalplanet > Privacy Statement

By using Verbalplanet.com you accept the terms of this privacy statement.

This privacy statement details how we use any information we collect from you. When you provide us with personal data and information, you are consenting to the processing of all such personal data and information as set out in this privacy statement. Please read this privacy statement carefully. Any changes to our privacy statement in the future will be posted to the website. You should revisit this page from time to time to review any changes that we may have made. Our privacy policy should be read in conjunction with our terms and conditions. If you have any questions or comments about how we handle your personal information, please contact us.

Appropriate technical measures are taken to protect your personal information including making a regular backup of our system and data. We have security measures in place to make sure any personal information we collect is secure. Your account is password protected and all information is on a secure server, which only a limited number of employees can access. If you think someone else knows your password, or is using it, tell us immediately and change your password by logging into your account.

Even though we take appropriate technical steps to protect your security we cannot and do not provide any guarantees regarding the effectiveness of the security we employ or our ability to prevent third parties from acting unlawfully and obtaining information that you provide to us. By using Verbalplanet.com you accept and acknowledge that data transmission over the internet cannot be guaranteed as 100% secure and that you use the website at your own risk.

We use your personal information: to answer your queries or complaints; to facilitate the provision of online language classes between registered Verbalplanet.com Language Students and registered Verbalplanet.com Language Teachers, to carry out administration; for general statistics, research and marketing; for obtaining any relevant professional advice; as may be required by law or in connection with legal proceedings (including where we intend to take legal proceedings), or as may be necessary to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights. We may also use aggregate information and statistics for the purpose of monitoring the web site usage in order to develop the web site and our services and may provide such aggregate information to third parties. These statistics will not include information that can be used to identify any individual.

Following registration on the Verbalplanet.com website, users are provided a communication system which does not require the disclosure of any individual users email address. Users agree and acknowledge that disclosure of their individual email address to other users of Verbalplanet.com is entirely at their own risk.

Communications between Verbalplanet.com users using any of the tools or functions we make available to you (including unopened messages sent via our messaging system) may be monitored by Verbalplanet.com staff for the purposes of preventing fraud and to prevent abuse of the Verbalplanet.com website.

If you have not registered with Verbalplanet.com but are simply making an enquiry or request for information, we will use your personal information to reply to your enquiry or request. We will not use this information for marketing purposes without your permission or unless you invite us to do so.

When you register with us, you must tell us: your desired username; desired password; your email address; the language you wish to learn; your country of residence; your local currency and your local time zone (if applicable). To use the Verbalplanet.com platform you will also be required to setup a Skype account and notify ourselves of your Skype name so that we may connect you to your chosen Language Teacher.

By booking lesson time through the Verbalplanet.com web site you consent to us notifying your chosen Language Teacher of your registered email address for the purposes of allowing your Language Teacher to invoice you directly for their lesson fee using PayPal or any other electronic invoicing service.

When you register with us, you must tell us: your desired username; desired password; your full name; your email address; your date of birth; your native language; your address; your country of residence; your local time zone (if applicable) and where you heard about us. By accepting the terms and conditions of use, all tutors agree to the publication of personal information supplied by them for the purposes of completing their tutor profile, including but not limited to, your first name, surname, age, native language,country of residence and city. To use the Verbalplanet.com platform you will also be required to setup a Skype account and notify ourselves of your Skype name as a condition of listing a tuition profile on Verbalplanet.com.

Verbalplanet.com does not store financial details including debit and credit card numbers nor do we share customer details with any 3rd parties. Users will be required to enter their financial details each time a transaction is made through Verbalplanet.com. Verbalplanet.com utilizes encryption technology to ensure the protection of your financial details whilst completing transactions.

When booking language lessons with a Language Teacher, Language Students are required to pay a booking fee to secure their lesson. Language Students who do not wish to pay using PayPal will be asked for details of a credit or debit card and a billing address. All of your details are encrypted using Verisign encryption technology to ensure the security of your personal information. For further details about the Verisign encryption technology please visit Verisign.com.

Under our Terms and Conditions of use, users are prohibited from engaging in any activity the purpose of which is to arrange lessons outside of the Verbalplanet site thereby avoiding the payment of any applicable fees. We reserve the right to monitor all communication through the Verbalplanet.com site for the purposes detecting activity designed to avoid our fee structure including but not limited to the sharing of email addresses, Skype contact details and website URL's.

Cookies are small text files which are sent to your browser by a web server and which we store on your personal computer's hard disk. Our system will issue cookies to your computer when you log on to the website. We use cookies on our site to: make it easier for you to log on; cut down the number of times you have to type in certain data; record the success of advertising, to target advertising and to track visitor usage. 

The cookies used on the website do not collect your personal information. Some of our web pages may contain invisible electronic tags that allow us to count users that have visited certain pages. These files are only used to identify which advertisements bring customers to our website and you cannot be identified by them. They are not issued by us but by the relevant advertising provider. 

Some of the cookies are strictly necessary for the functionality of the site while others are used to enhance the performance and your user experience. If you choose not to use cookies during your visit, you should be aware that certain functions and pages will not work as expected.

If you want to delete any cookies already on your computer, please refer to your browser vendor’s instructions by clicking “Help” in your browser menu. You can also find out more about cookies and how to delete and control them on www.aboutcookies.org or click “Help” in your browser menu.

By continuing to use the Verbalplanet.com web site you are giving your implied consent to the use of cookies in the manner described above.

Verbalplanet.com may from time to time wish to send you promotional material. If you do not wish to receive promotional correspondence please submit a request by email.

Verbalplanet.com reserves the right to contact all Users by email for the purposes of facilitating online language classes between registered Verbalplanet.com Language Students and registered Verbalplanet.com Language Teachers.

We keep personal data: for as long as is necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for; as required by law; or to enforce or defend legal claims. Sometimes we will keep information that you have deleted, for example messages sent by you to other registered Verbalplanet.com users. We will keep this information for a reasonable time.

You have the right to ask for a copy of all the information we hold about you (we will charge you a small fee for this) and to correct any inaccuracies. To obtain a copy of this information, please e-mail us. You can amend your details on the website at any time by accessing your account and updating your personal information.

The Verbalplanet.com website may contain links to other websites. The Owner is not responsible for the privacy policies of other sites and we advise you to read the privacy statement of every website that collects personal information from you.

## Get Started Today.  
Bring Learning a Language to Life.

#### Native teachers

#### Great pricing

#### Ulitmate flexibility
